(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T00:09:05.483621",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
アイドル革命進行中！ 今日の主役は夢の途中
[Title: Idol Revolution in Progress! Today's Protagonist in the Middle of a Dream]
世界一 可愛い
The cutest in the world,
私 宇宙一 可愛い
I'm the cutest in the universe!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear you more and more!
ご褒美は... 目を閉じて？
Your reward is... closing your eyes?
ちゅっ
Chu!
見つけてくれてサンキュー
Thank you for finding me!
愛してくれてサンキュー
Thank you for loving me!
生き甲斐にしちゃってもいいのよ
It's totally okay to make me your reason for living!
一人じゃ無理だ逆境
Hardships are impossible alone,
みんながいれば最強
but with everyone here, we're the strongest!
見つめ合って両想い
Gazing into each other's eyes, mutual love!
「好きになっちゃえ！」
"Fall in love with me!"
涙じゃ何も解決しないのわかってるから
I know that tears won't solve anything at all,
だから
So...
言葉で 行動で見せるよ
I'll show you through words and actions!
イェーイ！ だからお願い
Yeah! So please...
世界一可愛い
Cutest in the world!
宇宙一可愛い
Cutest in the universe!
もっともっと声だして よそ見はダメ
Shout out louder and louder, don't look away!
オッケー？
Okay?
瞬きも可愛い
Even her blinking is cute!
存在が可愛い
Her very existence is cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
ごほうびを
Here is your reward...
目を閉じて
Close your eyes...
チュッ！
*mwah*!
歌ってくれてサンキュー
Thank you for singing for me!
笑顔くれてサンキュー
Thank you for giving me your smile!
生きててよかったって思えた
It made me feel so glad to be alive!
外の見ためは愛キャッチ
My outer appearance catches love!
だけどやる気は再キャッチ
But my motivation catches back!
競い合って高め合って エースを狙え！
Competing and elevating each other, aim for the ace!
苦手からずっと逃げてちゃ 愛は届かないから
If you keep running from what you're bad at, love won't reach you!
だから何度も
So time and time again,
何度も挑もう
over and over, let's challenge it!
楽しんじゃおう！
Let's enjoy it all!
あざとくて可愛い
Calculatedly cute!
最高に可愛い
The absolute cutest!
私だけを愛して 応答くだーい！
Love only me and give me your response!
オッケー？
Okay?
泣いても可愛い
Cute even when crying!
存在が可愛い
Her very existence is cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
輝くから
Because I will shine,
約束ね
promise me!
上手に歌えてるかな？
I wonder if I'm singing well?
上手に踊れてるかな？
I wonder if I'm dancing well?
間違うの怖くなるけど
Getting scared of making mistakes, but...
できるできるできるできるー！
I can, I can, I can, I can do it!
信じてくれる人がいる
There are people who believe in me!
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
Through this song, I can stay connected with you.
忘れられないストーリー描いていこう！ 行くよー！
Let's paint an unforgettable story! Here we go!
世界一可愛い
Cutest in the world!
宇宙一可愛い
Cutest in the universe!
もっともっと声だして よそ見はダメ
Shout out louder and louder, don't look away!
オッケー？
Okay?
瞬きも可愛い
Even her blinking is cute!
存在が可愛い
Her very existence is cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
ごほうびは
Your reward is...
目を閉じて
Close your eyes...
チュッ！
*mwah*!
今日も鏡をチェック 最高のエガオ届ける
Checking the mirror again today, delivering the best smile.
才能に甘えないの
I don't rely on talent,
努力が大事よ
hard work is what matters!
ちゃんとお勉強して
Studying properly,
ちゃんとお片付けする
tidying up properly,
だって私はそう アイドルだもん
'cause I am an idol after all!
好きなタイプは私を大好きで 真面目・一途な人
My type is someone who loves me dearly, earnest and devoted.
ピッタリな君だけど 今じゃない
You're perfect, but not right now!
まつたんはもう大人だけど
Matsutan is an adult now, but...
君だけのものになれないの あぁごめん
I can't belong to just you, ah, I'm sorry!
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Promise me you'll keep loving me forever!
わがままなお願いね みんなのものでいたい
It's a selfish request, I know, I want to belong to everyone.
それでも私のこと 好きですか？
Even so, do you still love me?
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライト浴びて
Bathed in pink frills and the spotlight,
いつかきっとね 君だけのん〜♪私に
someday I'll surely be... mm~♪ yours alone,
今はまだ歌いたい
but for now I still want to sing!
現役アイドルちゅ〜
Active idol chu~
ずっとワクワクなのよ 朝 服選ぶのもして
I'm so excited every morning, even as I choose what to wear,
お気に入りマークしちゃうんだ
saving my favorite outfits!
キラキラメイクは今日もバッチリ
My sparkling makeup is perfectly done today, too.
やっと君と出会えた
I finally got to meet you!
ちょっと話せるだけなのに なんだか...
We only talk for a little bit, but somehow...
朝たぶん私早起きして
I probably woke up early this morning
ふたりの時間を楽しみにしてるから
because I was looking forward to our time together.
握手会 コンサート 会いに来て
Come see me at handshake events and concerts!
君のハッピーな姿 ずっと覚えているわ
I'll always remember seeing you so happy.
今週もない 来週も会いたいな
Not just this week, I want to see you next week too!
おしゃれなお洋服も準備して待ってるね
I'll get stylish clothes ready and wait for you, okay?
会えなくっても 頑張る君の姿は
Even when we can't meet, seeing you work hard
いつまでも好きでいる
makes me love you forever.
オフィシャルな想い
That's my official feeling!
わたしを推してくれた人にありがとう
Thank you to everyone who supports me!
こんなにキュートなわたしになれちゃうもん
Because of you, I can become this cute!
くるくるレースもきらり回ってる
My twirling lace sparkles as I spin around,
いくつになってもこのままここで輝く
and no matter how old I get, I'll keep shining right here!
ねぇねぇ教えて？ 今日も可愛い？
Hey, tell me... Am I cute today, too?
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Keep loving me forever, that's a promise!
わたしだって君のこと ずっとずっと大好き
Because I love you so, so much, too!
一生 わたしのこと好きですか？
Will you love me for the rest of your life?
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライトあびて
Bathed in the spotlight with my pink frills,
いつかきっとね 君だけのわたしに
someday I'll surely belong only to you.
今はまだ歌いたい 現役アイドルちゅ〜
But for now, I still want to sing as an active idol!
みんな！せーの！
Everyone! Ready... set...
こんばんわっしょい！
Good evening-wasshoi!
どうもホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル夏色まつりです！
Hello! I'm Hololive's purity representative, everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
ということで今年もやってまいりました、遅ればせながらの生誕誕生祭でございますよ！
So, it's that time of year again—a bit belated, but here is my Birthday Celebration Live!
まつりちゃんね、誕生日7月22日なんですけど
You see, my actual birthday is July 22nd,
まあ周年が6月ということでね、毎年11月にやらせていただいております
but since my anniversary is in June, I hold this every year in November!
なので今日も実質誕生日でございますね！はい、おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
So today is effectively my birthday too! Happy birthday to me! Thank you so much!
そして本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
And here is today's hashtag!
ドゥドゥドゥドゥドゥ… #夏色まつり生誕祭2025 でございます！
Drumroll... It's #NatsuiroMatsuriSeitansai2025!
いっぱいツイートしてトレンドに入れてあげてください、お願いします！
Please tweet a lot and help get it trending! I'm begging you!
あの、スクショとかもね、撮っていただいてツイートしてくれたら
Also, if you take screenshots and tweet them,
まつりちゃんが後でエゴサーチさせていただきますので、ぜひよろしくお願いしますね！見ちゃうよー！
I'll vanity search them later, so please do! I'll be watching~!
はい！そしてね、まあ皆さんもお気づきかなと思います！
All right! And I think many of you might have already noticed!
本日のタイトル「アイドル革命進行中！今日の主役は夢の途中」というタイトルにもあるようにでございますね
Just as today's title "Idol Revolution in Progress! Today's Main Attraction is Mid-Dream" suggests,
本日はアイドルさんの曲をたくさん詰め込んだ
today's live is packed with tons of awesome idol songs!
超とってもとっても可愛くて、ポップで、キュートで、ワクワクするようなライブになっていますので、最後まで楽しんでいってくださいねー！
It's super, super cute, pop, adorable, and exciting, so please enjoy it until the very end!
よろしくお願いします！コメントでもサイリウムを振ったりとか「可愛いよー」って言っちゃったりとか、たくさんしてくださいね！
Thank you! Feel free to wave lightsticks in the chat or type "You're so cute!" as much as you like!
ということで！この後は皆さまお待ちかねの… ゲストパートー！やったー！
And with that, coming up next is what you've all been waiting for... The guest segment! Yay!
はい
Hi!
ちょっとね、あの、まつりちゃん本気ダンスとかがすごく大好きなので
So, you know, Matsuri-chan really loves serious dancing and such,
あの、レッスンでね、お願い！やらせてください！って言って
so at lessons, I begged, "Please! Let us do this!"
フォーメーションとかもね、含め、みんなには頑張ってもらっていますので
Everyone's been working hard, including on the formations and everything,
あの、君の推しがもしいたら褒めてあげてください！
so if your favorite member is in this, please give them lots of praise!
ということで、ゲストパート準備してきちゃいますね！
With that said, I'm gonna go get ready for the guest part, okay?
じゃあみんな「ワクワク」ってコメントして待ってて？ じゃあ行ってきまーす！
So everyone, wait while commenting "Waku Waku" (excited)! Off I go!
ワクワク！ワクワク！ワクワクワクワクワクワク...
Waku waku! Waku waku! Waku waku waku waku...
サクラあっぱれーしょん
[Sakura Apparation]
hey yo, d.e.m.p.a from akihabara to everywhere
さあさあ寄ってらっしゃい 見てらっしゃい もう一切合切やっちゃいな
Come one, come all, gather round and take a look, just go all out!
ありったけのカワイイと楽しいこと詰め込んで
Packed full of all the cuteness and fun we've got!
さあ少年少女よ 船に乗っていざ出航じゃ
Now then, boys and girls, board the ship and set sail!
hey yo, d.e.m.p.a from japanese hot area
みんな元気ですか？ 声聞かせて？ はいでんぱー！（でんぱー！）
How is everyone doing? Let me hear your voices! Say Denpa! (Denpa!)
ありがとさん もはや準備はバッチリのようなのね（OK!）
Thank you! Looks like you're all set and ready to go! (OK!)
さあ今からでっかい船に乗っていざ出航じゃ
Now then, board the big ship and set sail!
さあみんな ダンスダンスダンス 草履履いてビラカンひらり
Come on everyone, dance dance dance, put on straw sandals, hair ornaments fluttering!
カッコつけても パンツパンツパンツ はみ出てる
Even when trying to look cool, underwear, underwear, underwear is sticking out!
めっちゃくちゃのドキュメンタリー
A chaotic documentary,
それが僕らにとってのファンタジー
and that's a fantasy for us!
春夏秋冬 感じるんだ 呼んでるんだ あ ソレソレソレソレ
Feel the four seasons, they're calling out to us, ah sore sore sore sore!
シェイプシェイプシェイプ 胸を張っては 汗たらり
Shape shape shape, stand tall with chest out, sweat dripping down
突っ走っても こっちこっちこっち 逆方向
Dash forward, but over here, over here, going in the wrong direction!
青春はそれでいいのだ
That's what youth is all about!
勘違いも味方にしちゃうのだ
Even misunderstandings become our allies!
森羅万象 歌え日本 踊れ日本 あ ソレソレソレ（よいしょ！）
All creation, sing Japan, dance Japan, ah sore sore sore (Yoisho!)
ちんとんしゃんしゃんと どこまでも ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Chin ton shan shan, wherever you go, power through with full blast!
あっちもこっちもそっちも 祭りだ わっしょい あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Over there, over here, over where, it's a festival! Wasshoi! Splendid, splendid adventure!
大和の国へ 摩訶不思議な言霊（OK!）
To the land of Yamato, mysterious power of words (OK!)
奇想天外さ いつまでも（さいさい！） 神様 仏様 兎様
Bizarre and wild forever and ever! (Sai sai!) Gods, Buddha, Rabbits!
月に祈って拝んで君思って
Praying to the moon, worshiping, thinking of you,
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
severing all half-hearted feelings!
とりあえずいいか？ 黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, are you ready? Shut up and follow me!
嗚呼 嗚呼
Ah, ah
君の未来を明るく照らすなんて お茶の子さいさいさい
Brightening up your future is a total piece of cake!
百花繚乱 大和撫子たちよ どでかい花火を上げましょうね
A profusion of flowers, Yamato Nadeshiko, let's set off huge fireworks!
ほら踊る阿呆に見る阿呆 同じ阿呆なら踊らニャ損損
Look, fools dancing and fools watching, if we're both fools, it's a loss not to dance!
さあみんな ダンスダンスダンス さらし巻いておへそちらり
Come on everyone, dance dance dance, wrapped in sarashi, belly button peeking through
靴脱いだら ソックソックソック 破れてる
Take off your shoes, socks, socks, socks are torn!
どったんばったんなこのステージ
This hectic, chaotic stage,
それが私にとっての正義（ジャスティス！）
that's my kind of justice! (Justice!)
古今東西 羽ばたくんだ 聞こえるんだ あ ソレソレソレソレ
All times and places, flap your wings, I can hear it, ah sore sore sore sore!
シェイクシェイクシェイク 腕を振っては 涙キラリ
Shake shake shake, wave your arms, tears glistening
強がっても きゅんきゅんきゅん 苦しいの
Even pretending to be tough, my heart throbs with pain
乙女はそれでいいのだ
That's fine for a maiden!
マイナスも味方にしちゃうのだ
We even turn negatives into our strength!
情意投合 愛してんんだ みんな大好きだ だだだだだ
Mutual understanding, I love you, I love you all so so so much!
ちんとんしゃんしゃんと どこまでも（はいはい！）
Chin ton shan shan, wherever you go (Hai hai!)
ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Power through with full blast!
あっちもこっちもそっちも 祭りだ わっしょい あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Over there, over here, over where, it's a festival! Wasshoi! Splendid, splendid adventure!
大和の国へ 摩訶不思議な言霊（それそれそれそれ！）
To the land of Yamato, mysterious power of words (Sore sore sore sore!)
奇想天外さ いつまでも（ガッテン！） 神様 仏様 兎様
Bizarre and wild forever and ever! (Got it!) Gods, Buddha, Rabbits!
月に祈って拝んで君思って
Praying to the moon, worshiping, thinking of you,
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
severing all half-hearted feelings!
とりあえずいいか？ 黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, are you ready? Shut up and follow me!
嗚呼 嗚呼
Ah, ah
君の未来を明るく照らすなんて お茶の子さいさいさい
Brightening up your future is a total piece of cake!
満月の下で踊りましょう
Let's dance under the full moon
桜舞い散る季節と歌いましょう
Let's sing with the season of fluttering cherry blossoms
君といつかまた出会うその日まで
Until the day we meet again somewhere
だから意地っぱりさんも 照れ屋さんもしゃお屋さんも あなたも
So stubborn ones, shy ones, greengrocers, and you too
忘れないで ばいばいさようなら（ばいばーい！）
Don't forget, bye-bye, farewell! (Bye-bye!)
逃げない!!
Don't Run Away!!
時間たてば 事務的にやってくる
As time passes, it comes around automatically
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
A tomorrow like that isn't our tomorrow
逃げたい
I want to run away...
じゃあどこに逃げればいいのかな
...then where should I run to?
曖昧な場所では
In an ambiguous place,
何にも変われない
nothing can ever change.
立ち向かえとか やり直せるよとか 間違った道を
Telling me to face it or that I can start over on a mistaken path...
何度もやり直せる
...saying I can restart again and again,
あなた一体 誰ですか？
who on earth are you?
論点ずれてる人たち なんて押しのけて
Pushing aside those people who miss the point entirely,
自分の道 作らなくちゃ
I have to forge my own path.
“失敗しない”なんて 契約を人は 誰とも結んではいない
No one has ever made a contract promising 'I won't fail.'
“幸せになります”とは誓いいつか 昔大事な人と 約束したはずだ
I must have promised an important person long ago that 'I will be happy.'
大人になるために 早く忘れることだけ覚え
To become an adult, learning only how to forget quickly,
無理に目を背けたら
if you forcibly avert your eyes,
10年後の子供を 救えないよ
you won't be able to save the child ten years from now.
全部自分が悪いと 責める君に伝えたい
I want to tell you, who blame yourself for everything,
同じ言葉を人に 言わない君を 誰責められない
no one can blame you for not saying those same words to others.
逃げない
I won't run away.
じゃあどこに向かえばいいのかな
Then where should I head toward?
辛さの根源を 見つめ直せる場所
A place where I can re-examine the root of my pain.
いきなり 空を飛ぶ 方法なんて
A way to suddenly fly in the sky—
知らない
I don't know one.
悪と暇の 行き来は 誰もしないで！
Don't go back and forth between evil and boredom!
“生きろ”とか“甦れ”とか もういい
'Live on' or 'Be revived,' enough already!
逆に逃げて もういいんだよとかいう
Telling me 'It's okay to run away instead'...
私は一体 誰ですか？
...who on earth am I?
分かってくれている 瞳の輝きが
There are people whose shining eyes show they understand,
消えてないって 証明してくれた 人たちがいる
proving to me that it hasn't faded away.
時間たてば 事務的にやってくる
As time passes, it comes around automatically
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
A tomorrow like that isn't our tomorrow
足に訊ねる 走れるか
Asking my feet: can you run?
指に訊ねる 開ける？
Asking my fingers: can you open?
体温に訊ねる 血潮で導いて いけるだろうか
Asking my body temperature: can my surging blood lead the way?
始まりの合図は他の 誰にも決めさせたくない
I won't let anyone else decide the signal to start.
教科書の先の現代は
The present era beyond the textbooks—
我々が作っていくから
—is something we will create ourselves.
だから逃げない
So I won't run away.
私（みんな）は逃げない
We won't run away.
逃げたい君を
I won't leave behind
置いては行かない
you, who want to run.
じゃなきゃ意味ない
Otherwise, it would be meaningless.
手放したいことない
There's nothing I want to let go of.
顔を見なくなって 君を知ってる
Even without seeing your face, I know you.
苦しめる 渦の中
In the midst of the tormenting vortex,
頭脳の目 広げて
open the eyes of your mind,
別の角度で 見てごらん
and try looking from a different angle.
そこだけ 逃げないで
Just don't run away from that.
時間たてば 事務的にやってくる
As time passes, it comes around automatically
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
A tomorrow like that isn't our tomorrow
「とくベチュ、して」
"Give me special kisses"
Oh baby "I love you" じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough
一番大事がいい
I want to be what matters to you most
君が作るオリジナルの
With the original kind of love...
特別、チューして。
...that you create, give me a special kiss.
眩しくて 目が覚めて
The light is so bright as I wake up,
愛おしく思ってよ
Please hold me dear to your heart.
眠り姫のように 優しく口付けて
Kiss me gently like Sleeping Beauty.
ゴミめいた この世界
In this world full of trash,
ピュアがかかる 君がいる
You are here, so pure and bright.
全てに触れずに 2人だけでいよう
Let's leave everything else untouched and be just the two of us.
私のこと 独占して
Keep me all to yourself,
君だけのモノになってもいい
I wouldn't mind belonging only to you.
なんでもある日の 「なんでもない」 気付いてね
On an ordinary day, please notice when I say "it's nothing."
Oh baby "I love you" じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough,
君の 「特別」 にして
Make me your "special one."
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, give me a kiss, I'm already...
君でいっぱいよ
...so completely full of you.
ほどけない リボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot,
小指 キュッて縛って
Tie our pinky fingers tight together.
そうよ 一生 一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want us to be together for life,
とくべチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss from you.
2人きり 週末は
Just the two of us on the weekend,
奏でてよ ハーモニー
Play a sweet harmony for us.
流れ星見たら 私を想ってほしい
If you see a shooting star, I want you to think of me.
あまあまな君なのに
You're usually so sweet to me,
広い街 呑み込まれ
But swallowed up by the big city,
戦う姿に 大きいはなまるだね
Seeing you fight hard deserves a giant gold star!
好きなところ、優しいとこ。
What I like about you is how gentle you are.
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ。
What I dislike about you is also how gentle you are.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone else,
私だけ 独り占め!
I'm keeping you all to myself!
う〜 だって 今までの人と
Ooh, because someone just like everyone before...
同じはいらないんです
...is not what I need.
ねぇ もっと Give me more love 私のため
Hey, give me more love, I want you to live...
生きてほしいんです
...just for my sake.
だから ウサギと私は
That's why, just like a rabbit,
さみしくさせないで
don't leave me feeling lonely.
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not even possessive at all,
苦しいのが好き
I actually love feeling bound.
ショートケーキ イチゴみたいに 座ってもいい?
Can I sit on top like the strawberry on a strawberry shortcake?
赤く甘い恋だもん
Because this is a red, sweet love.
誰かにあげた 大好きも
Even the love you gave to someone else before,
返してもらって全部私に ちょーだい
get it back and give it all to me!
もっと!
Give me more!
君は神様が作る
You are a miracle of a person...
奇跡のようなヒト
...created by God Himself.
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your pouting face, your sleeping face too,
守ってあげるね
I will protect them all for you.
Oh baby "I love you" じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough,
君の 「特別」 にして
Make me your "special one."
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, give me a kiss, I'm already...
君でいっぱいよ
...so completely full of you.
ほどけない リボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot,
小指 キュッて縛って
Tie our pinky fingers tight together.
ねぇ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, make it our first and last...
とくべチュにしてね
...special kiss, okay?
ミルクで乾杯〜
Cheers with milk!
砂糖盛ったら甘〜い
Add lots of sugar and it's so sweet!
レンジでちんしてあったか〜い
Microwave it up and it's warm!
Let's go ぱ ぴ ぷ ぺ ポ〜ン!
Let's go! Pa, pi, pu, pe, pop!
人生万歳!
Hurrah for life!
この先10年安態〜
Set for the next 10 years~
盛れてバズったらはんぱな〜い
If we look cute and go viral, it'll be crazy!
Let's go ぱ ぴ ぷ ぺ ポ〜ン!
Let's go! Pa, pi, pu, pe, pop!
ぴゅんぴゅんです
Pyun pyun!
ろんろんです
Ron ron!
はっぴーです
Happy!
問題な〜いっす 半端な〜いっす ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem at all! Unreal! Discotheque bambina!
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
So careless! So easy! So vague! Doing this forever...
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
...in a pa-pi-pu-pe-po kind of mood,
ポップに生きていこう
let's live pops-style!
ぱ ぴ ぷ ぺ ポ〜ン!
Pa, pi, pu, pe, pop!
Hi! Hi!
ぱ ぴ ぷ ぺ ポ〜ン!
Pa, pi, pu, pe, pop!
Hi! Hi!
毎日毎日 パーリーピーポー Let me yeah! dancing
Every single day, party people! Let me yeah! Dancing!
横ノリ 縦ノリ わるノリで
Grooving side-to-side, up-and-down, or getting wild!
映画のキャストみたいに
Like movie cast members,
ボンキュのボンな美ボディ
with luscious, gorgeous bodies,
弾けて smile delight
bursting with smile delight!
なんでスネてんの?
Why are you pouting?
うるさい!
Shut up!
なんで泣いてんの? あっちいって!
Why are you crying? Go away!
なんで？ なんで？
Why? Why?
だって だって 女の子だもん
'Cause, 'cause, I'm a girl!
なんで帰っちゃうの？
Why are you leaving?
(触んないで！) なんで怒ってんの？ あーもう
(Don't touch me!) Why are you mad? Ah, jeez!
わかってよ 言わなくても わかってよ！
Understand me, even if I don't say it! Understand me!
あ、ごめん
Ah, sorry!
やっぱ好きー！
I actually love you!
めんどくさっ
How annoying...
きゅんきゅんです ピュンピュンです るんるんです きゃっきゃーです はっぴーです
Fluttering heart, zooms, feeling happy, giggly, and full of joy!
問題ないっす 半端ないっす 我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, super intense, we are discotheque bambinas!
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
Relaxed, taking it easy, keeping it vague, forever like this!
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていこう
With a PaPiPuPePo vibe, let's live pop!
ぱぴぷぺPOP！
PaPiPuPe POP!
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺPOP！
PaPiPuPe POP!
Hi! Hi!
ぱっと咲いて Shy
Blooming brightly, shyly
ピアニシモで kiss
Kissing in pianissimo
プロいラップ yo
Pro-level rap, yo!
ペプシ飲んで「あ～」
Drinking Pepsi with an "Ah~"
ポップに踊ろう ポップに踊ろう
Let's dance pop, let's dance pop!
さあLet's, さあLet's Go, Funny Funny time!
Come on let's, come on let's go, funny funny time!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺー
Peppeke peppee, peppeke peppee
きゅんです 3 2 1
Heart fluttering, 3 2 1!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺー
Peppeke peppee, peppeke peppee
おこです 3 2 1
Pouting mad, 3 2 1!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺー
Peppeke peppee, peppeke peppee
笑顔で 3 2 1
Smile, 3 2 1!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺー
Peppeke peppee, peppeke peppee
変顔 3 2 1
Funny face, 3 2 1!
なんかいい感じ (もしもーし？)
Feels pretty good! (Hello?)
なんか嬉しいね (え、どしたん？)
Kinda feeling happy, right? (Huh, what's wrong?)
なんかなんか、やっぱ、やっぱ、女の子だもん
Like, after all, after all, I'm a girl!
なんかハッピーです (うん、そんで？)
Kinda feeling happy! (Yeah, and?)
なんか有頂天です
On cloud nine!
あーもう 幸やです！
Ah jeez, I'm so happy!
聞いてよ 幸やです！ ちょっと！ 話してっからさ 聞いてー！
Listen to me, I'm happy! Hold on! I'm talking, so listen!
…へーそうなんだ
...Oh, is that so?
最高です 絶頂です ミラクルです ウルトラです ハイパーです
Supreme, peak, miraculous, ultra, hyper!
とんでもないっす 尋常ないっす 我々アーティスティックなパンピーじゃん
Incredible, extraordinary, we're artistic average people!
ちょっとだけ素ボンクラです 大概です ずっとこうやって
A bit simple-minded, but mostly fine, keeping it like this forever!
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていこう
With a PaPiPuPePo vibe, let's live pop!
ぱぴぷぺPOP！
PaPiPuPe POP!
ミルクで乾杯～
Cheers with milk~
砂糖混ぜたらあんま～い
Mixing in sugar makes it so sweet~
レンジでちんしてあったか～い
Microwaved to make it warm~
Let's Go ぱぴぷぺPOP yo
Let's Go PaPiPuPe POP yo
人生万歳～ この先10年安泰～
Hurrah for life~ set for the next ten years~
盛れてバズったらはんぱな～い
Looking great and going viral, it's amazing~
Let's Go ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's Go PaPiPuPe POP
ぱぴぷぺPOP！ ぱぴぷぺPOP！ ぱぴぷぺ Poppin'! Hoppin'!
PaPiPuPe POP! PaPiPuPe POP! PaPiPuPe Poppin'! Hoppin'!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴPOP
PaPiPuPePo, PaPiPuPePo, PaPiPOP
愛チュセヨ Lovin' you アモーレ アミーゴ
Give me love, Lovin' you, amore, amigo!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴPOP
PaPiPuPePo, PaPiPuPePo, PaPiPOP
A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O People
Be Poppin' Poppin' Poppin' Poppin' POP!
POP POP POP POP POP!
最大級 最高級 最上級 ハイスペックな人生です
Maximum, top-tier, highest-grade high-spec life!
アイラブユー アイフォーユー だけど君がいないと悲しいな
I love you, I for you, but without you, it's so sad.
ほんとはね やっぱりね 結局ね ずっとこうやって
Honestly, after all, in the end, wanting to keep living like this forever...
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていたい
With a PaPiPuPePo vibe, I want to live pop!
ぱぴぷぺPOP！
PaPiPuPe POP!
きゅんきゅんです ピュンピュンです るんるんです きゃっきゃーです はっぴーです
Fluttering heart, zooms, feeling happy, giggly, and full of joy!
問題ないっす 半端ないっす 我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, super intense, we are discotheque bambinas!
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
Relaxed, taking it easy, keeping it vague, forever like this!
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていこう
With a PaPiPuPePo vibe, let's live pop!
ぱーで ぴーで ぽーで ぷーで POPにENJOY
Pa and pi and po and pu, enjoy in pop!
あれこれ どれそれ 楽しいね (Hi!)
This and that, which and what, so much fun! (Hi!)
ぱーで ぴーで ぽーで ぷーで POPにENJOY
Pa and pi and po and pu, enjoy in pop!
あれこれ どれそれ 楽しいね (Hi!)
This and that, which and what, so much fun! (Hi!)
ぱぴぷぺPOP！ ぱぴぷぺPOP！ ぱぴぷぺPOP！
PaPiPuPe POP! PaPiPuPe POP! PaPiPuPe POP!
ぱぴぷぺ Poppin', POP!
PaPiPuPe Poppin', POP!
みんなー、ゲストパートどうだったー？ 可愛かったー？ ありがとうございます！
Everyone, how was the guest part? Was it cute? Thank you so much!
ということでね、すごい続けてやってしまったんですが
So anyway, I went through all of them back-to-back, but...
まず「サクラ・アパラチオン」はAZKiちゃんとルーナちゃんとリリカに出ていただきました
First off, for "Sakura Apparition", AZKi-chan, Luna-chan, and Lirika joined me!
なんかすごいサクラというか春っぽいね、ピンクな感じのメンバーを呼びました
I called up members with a cherry blossom, spring-like, pink vibe.
リリカすごい頑張ってたよなー。練習中も「あ、あ、できない～！」って言いながら頑張ってたリリカ。
Lirika worked really hard! Even during practice she kept saying "Ah, I can't do it~!", but she gave it her all!
そして次、「逃げない」ね。
And next was "Nigenai".
「逃げない」は結構古めの曲なんですけれど、まつりがすごい大好きで一番推していたゆるめるモ！さんの楽曲で
"Nigenai" is a bit of an older song, but it's by You'll Melt More!, a group I absolutely loved and was my top favorite...
ここで歌えてすごく嬉しかったです。ありがとうございますね。
...and I was so happy to sing it here! Thank you so much!
そして「トクベチュして」は、もう難しかった！
And "Tokubetchu Shite" was just so hard!
すごい難しかったんだから。だってさ、1番と2番でサビの振り付け違うしさ、めっちゃ難しかったよ。
It was crazy hard! The chorus choreography was different in the 1st and 2nd verses, so it was super tough!
=LOVEさんの曲は毎回難しいけど、すごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね。
=LOVE's songs are always tough, but dancing to them is super fun!
はい。そして「ぱぴぷぺPOP！」
Right. And then "PaPiPuPe POP!"
これ、ずっとこうやってやってるから、すごい疲れて、汗だくになった。
Since we were jumping around like this the whole time, I got so tired and ended up drenched in sweat!
凄かったよ！ 練習中の時も汗だくすぎて、「ちょっと待って…ちょっと疲れた…」とか言ったりして
It was intense! Even in practice we were sweating so much, saying "Wait a sec... I'm exhausted..."
みんなでわちゃわちゃしながら練習し続けましたけど、すごい楽しかったでございます。
We kept practicing while messing around together, and it was so much fun!
そして、ちょっと紹介できてなかった、こちらのステージ！
And next, here is the stage that I hadn't introduced yet!
じゃーん！ かわいい～！ すっごい可愛く作っていただきました。
Ta-da! So cute~! They made it super cute for me!
さあ あの アイドルソングたちばかりなので
So, um, since these are all idol songs...
アイドルステージっていう感じにしてくださいって言ってね
I asked them to make it look like an "idol stage"...
こんな感じになりましたよ
and this is how it turned out!
あの 提灯もね あるけどさ
Um, there are lanterns too, but...
なんかすごい あの 主張しすぎないというか いい意味でね
they don't stand out too much, in a good way.
あの なんかパステルな ピンクとか ま これ色変わるんですけど
Like, pastel pink and all... though these change colors...
すごい可愛い感じにしてくれて
They made it look super cute!
でね 風船もね これね 色変わるんですよ 実はね
And the balloons, these actually change colors too, surprisingly!
なんかちょっと その辺も注目していただきたいなと 思いますね
So I hope you'll pay attention to those details as well.
めっちゃ可愛いでしょう
Isn't it super cute?
あの 後で 1個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います
Um, I think I'll take one home with me later!
はい そして
Alright, and...
あのね みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど
you know, I wonder if you noticed, but...
あのね まつりすがね いるわけですよ
Matsuris is here, you see!
そう あのね 周年 1期生の周年ライブのときにはいなかったんですよ
Yeah, during the 1st gen anniversary live, they weren't here!
ね エビフライオンがね いたの 代わりに
Right? Ebi-fry-on was here instead!
他のさ はーとんとかはさ あの ちゃんと はーとんとしていたのに リスナーさんの姿でいたのに
The other ones, like Haaton, were properly there as Haaton, in their listener forms...
まつりだけね まつりすがいなくてエビフライオンだったんで 今回
Only for Matsuri, there was no Matsuris, just Ebi-fry-on...
あの 良かったね これって
So, I'm really glad about this, you know?
ということで
And so!
早速 続いての曲行きましょうか
Let's move on to the next song right away!
続いての曲も アイドルソングでございますよ
The next one is an idol song as well!
それでは聞いてください アイドルソング
So please listen to... IDOL SONG.
ねぇ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
すっごい愛をあげたい
I want to give super-duper love.
この命の使い方を
How to use this life of mine...
君に愛されたい
I want to be loved by you.
はい えくぼは恋の落とし穴 夢中にさせちゃうぞ
Yup! Dimples are love's trap, I'll make you fall crazy for me!
埼玉県から来ました フレッシュレモンになりたいの
I came from Saitama, I wanna be a fresh lemon!
ファンの方々が恋人です
The fans are my lovers!
真面目なアイドル 真面目にアイドル
Serious idol, seriously an idol!
連休 24時間ずっと 笑顔でうさぴょん
Holidays, 24 hours non-stop, smiling Usa-pyon!
はい あなたの心にホールインワン
Yup! A hole-in-one into your heart!
あなたのハートにアクセスします
Accessing your heart!
みんなのドキドキにシュートします
Shooting straight into everyone's hearts!
なんでもいいからレスください
Give me a response, anything will do!
高まりみなさん
Get pumped, everyone!
よーし 今日も可愛い 小指ーむ
Alright! Cute again today, Pinky Beam!
ねぇ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
本当はわからないけど
I don't really know, but...
幸せに似てるシャンプーの香りを見つけたの
I found a shampoo scent that feels like happiness.
歌で人の気持ち 明るくできるように
So that my singing can brighten people's spirits.
きっと人生にこじつけてる人がいると思ったから
Because I thought someone out there might be clinging onto it for life.
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to love, keep it simple.
好きでいいよ もっと叫べ
It's okay to love, shout it louder.
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to love, keep it simple.
好きでいいよ もっと叫べ イェーイ
It's okay to love, shout it louder, yeah!
はい めちゃくちゃ喋るのが苦手
Yup! Super bad at speaking in public!
可愛い自分キモい
Thinking I'm cute is gross!
世界のルールを歌って踊って破壊する
Singing, dancing, breaking the world's rules!
燃える瞳 燃える髪の毛 見た目純白 中身は真っ黒
Burning roots, burning hair, pure white looks, pitch black inside!
ちょっぴりおバカな天才児 感染症
A slightly silly genius kid, Infectious Disease!
魅力的で誘惑に負けるだけ
Attractive, just giving in to temptation!
あっという間にミルキー 1234 魔法にかかれ
In a flash, milky, 1-2-3-4, fall under the spell!
あっ 赤くなっちゃった
Ah, I turned all red!
童貞なんて言ったことないよ
I've never said "virgin" before!
ピンクのマシュマロが出ます
Pink marshmallows pop out!
3時のおやつはマカロン焼き
3 PM snack is baked macarons!
ふわふわガール目指し中
Aiming to be a fluffy girl!
ねぇ アイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is so fun.
いっぱい愛がまわってる
So much love going around.
ステージから見る景色がずっと続いたらいいのにな
I wish this view from the stage could last forever.
でももし君が高いところから落としたとしても
But even if you drop me down from a high place...
必要な分の幸せは
The happiness you needed...
あげられていたのかな
I wonder if I was able to give it to you.
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love, be more daring.
好きでいいよ もっと叫べ
It's okay to love, shout it louder.
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love, be more daring.
好きでいいよ もっと叫べ
It's okay to love, shout it louder, whoo!
はい 360度どこから見てもアイドル
Yup! An idol from 360 degrees, no matter where you look!
出席番号はラッキーセブン
Attendance number is Lucky Seven!
好きになってもいいですか？
Is it okay if I fall in love with you?
俺の妹がこんなに可愛いわけがないちゃん
My Little Sister Can't Be This Cute-chan!
ぷりぷり ぴちぴちでしょ？
Squishy, fresh and plump, right?
コンニチハ ネギネギ
Hello, Negi-negi!
せる 愛せる ランドセル
Cell, loveable, Randoseru backpack!
今日も明日も明後日もキラキラパワー
Sparkling power today, tomorrow, and the day after!
センコー 頑張っていこう！
Let's do our best, Senko!
みんなの目線はいただきまゆゆ
I'll take everyone's gaze, Mayuyu!
抱きしめて甘えん坊なみんなのともとも
Hug me, everyone's pampered Tomotomo!
ねぇ アイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is so fun.
いっぱい愛がまわってる
So much love going around.
ステージから見る景色が
The view from the stage...
ずっと特別なものさ
It's always been something special,
恋愛ドラマになりたい
I want to become a romantic drama.
すっごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you so much love,
この命の使い方を
teaching you how to use this life,
君に愛されたい
I want to be loved by you.
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to like me, make it simpler.
好きでいいよ もっと雑で
It's okay to like me, even carelessly.
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to like me, make it simpler.
好きでいいよ もっと雑で
It's okay to like me, even carelessly.
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to like me, more boldly!
好きでいいよ もっと雑で
It's okay to like me, even carelessly.
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to like me, more boldly!
好きでいいよ もっと雑で
It's okay to like me, even carelessly.
優しさ キス 奇跡も キラキラ輝け 頑張っていきましょう！
Kindness, kisses, miracles, shine brightly! Let me do my best!
わー！ びっくりしたでしょ？
Whoa! Surprised, right?
今日の私が昨日より可愛いなんて！
Today's me is even cuter than yesterday!
ぎゅーって ぎゅーって ぎゅーしたい 次の流行りは次の地雷
Hugs, hugs, I want to hug you tight! The next trend is the next landmine,
踏まないように知っとかなくちゃ でもギュッとしたら大爆発
I gotta know so I don't step on it, but hugging tight causes a huge explosion!
散りたい 死にたい 死にたい 散りたい
Want to scatter, want to die, want to die, want to scatter,
くない 知りたくない ずっと尊い
No! Don't wanna know! Forever precious!
たら尊い なぜなぜ分からない
If it's precious, why, why don't I get it?
私 ちー ちー ちー ちーぎゅう
I'm a chi- chi- chi- chi-gyuu!
ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！
Hug! Hug! Hug! Hug! Hug!
過去最年少 未来最年少
Youngest in the past, youngest in the future!
過去最大級 未来勝手ら
Biggest in the past, the future is whatever we want!
未来チラチラ 福袋みたい
Glancing at the future, like a lucky bag!
好きな色が見えたから これにしよう
I saw my favorite color, so let's go with this!
頑張らなくていいよー イェーイ！
You don't have to try so hard~ Yay!
ちーぎゅう
Chi-gyuu
ちーぎゅう ちーぎゅう ちーぎゅう
Chi-gyuu, chi-gyuu, chi-gyuu!
雑音は無視 鳴らしちゃうチャイム
Ignore the noise, ring the chime!
間違っても可愛くなれるチネ
Even if you make a mistake, you can still become cute!
一番可愛い時に死みたい
Want to pass away while at my absolute cutest!
言いなら全然死なないね
If that's the condition, I'm never gonna die!
私 ちー ちー ちー ちーぎゅう
I'm a chi- chi- chi- chi-gyuu!
私 ちー ちー ちー
I'm a chi- chi- chi-
死んでる暇ない 可愛いと言いたい
No time to die, I want to say you're cute!
過去最年少 未来最年少
Youngest in the past, youngest in the future!
いま捨てちゃおう 未来全部入り
Let's throw it away now, packed with all the future!
好きなシチュエーションが
My favorite scenario...
今私に合いたがってる
...is dying to meet me right now!
すごく素敵な女もこんな
Even an amazingly wonderful girl...
んだわー
...is like this!
何歳になっても可愛いね、じゃないの！
Don't tell me "You're cute no matter how old you get"!
こっちは努力して可愛いやってんの！
I'm putting in effort to be cute here!
何十何歳だったら可愛いの？
How old am I supposed to be to be cute?
本当はそんなの当たり前だもん！
I mean, that should be obvious!
言わせないでよ！そっちから言って！
Don't make me say it! Say it yourselves!
「今日も可愛いね」でしょ！
It's "You're cute today too!", right?!
今日も可愛いね！
"You're cute today too!"
可愛いね！
"So cute!"
可愛い！
"Cute!"
今日も可愛い！
"Cute today too!"
私、今日も可愛いね！
I'm cute today too!
よし、今日も可愛いぞ！
Alright, I'm cute today as well!
未来チラチラ おりこうお祝い
Glancing at the future, clever celebration!
過去見つけては元に戻して
Whenever I find the past, I put it back!
未来チラチラ 可愛いからこそ
Glancing at the future, precisely because I'm cute,
今を最も特に生きたい
I want to live the present to the absolute fullest!
過去最年少 未来最年少
Youngest in the past, youngest in the future!
過去最大級 未来勝手ら
Biggest in the past, the future is whatever we want!
未来チラチラ 福袋みたい
Glancing at the future, like a lucky bag!
好きな色が見えたから これにしよう
I saw my favorite color, so let me pick this!
頑張らなくていいよー イェーイ！
You don't have to try so hard~ Yay!
君っぽいな 恋のSOS
So like you, a love's SOS.
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been hurting all this time.
早くレスキュー
Rescue me quickly!
好きのテレパシーに早く気づいて
Hurry and notice my telepathy of love!
初めて出会ったときから
Ever since we first met,
ずっと心が震えてたんだよ
my heart has been trembling non-stop.
無意識に意識しちゃう
Unconsciously, I keep becoming conscious of you.
この感じはきっと
This feeling must surely be...
急上昇で
...rising rapidly,
目と目合うだけで顔が熱いの
my face burns up just by making eye contact.
話しかけられて
When you speak to me...
ドキドキして
My heart is pounding,
恋を届けないと
if I don't send my love...
ツンとすればいいな こんな気持ちは
I wish I could play it cool, these feelings...
似合わない恋心
...of a crush don't suit me.
星占いなら SO-SO
According to my horoscope, it's so-so.
友達なんかじゃないよ
We're not just friends,
ときめいてる
my heart is fluttering.
君にフリフリ 恋のSOS
Waving a love S.O.S to you,
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
my chest aches all the time.
早くレスキュー 好きのテレパシーに
Rescue me quickly, notice my love telepathy
早く気づいて
as soon as possible!
これもフリフリ 恋のSOS
This is also waving a love S.O.S,
もっと君に近づきたい
I want to get closer to you.
終わらせて 片思い MY HEART
End this unrequited love, my heart,
全部 抱きしめて
embrace it all!
君が好きな音楽や
The music you like,
映画のことリサーチして
and researching movies...
SNS見る度に
Every time I check SNS,
いいね押すのアピールだよ
hitting 'like' is my way of showing it.
ぐぐっと君のこと考えて
Thinking about you so deeply,
遠押ししながら
while trying to drop subtle hints...
枕蹴飛ばした
I kicked my pillow,
明日はどんな服着ていこうかな
wondering what clothes I should wear tomorrow.
君を思うだけで なんか照れる
Just thinking of you makes me feel so shy.
君の名前を呼べば
If I call out your name,
ただそれだけでも Dreaming Dreaming
even just that is dreaming, dreaming.
溺れそうだ 私は
I feel like I'm drowning,
助け出して
please save me!
君にフリフリ 恋のSOS
Waving a love S.O.S to you,
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
my chest aches all the time.
早くレスキュー 好きのテレパシーに
Rescue me quickly, notice my love telepathy
早く気づいて
as soon as possible!
これもフリフリ 恋のSOS
This is also waving a love S.O.S,
もっと君に近づきたい
I want to get closer to you.
終わらせて 片思い MY HEART
End this unrequited love, my heart,
全部 抱きしめて
embrace it all!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our brand-new heartbeats resonate!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
In the best time, with the best friends!
キラメキ輪になって
Forming a glittering circle!
覚えてるかな 最初の一歩
Do you remember? That very first step,
私 声が震えていた
my voice was trembling.
あの日から続く未来は
The future that continues from that day,
みんなと掴んだんだよ
we seized it together with everyone!
もっともっともっと 加速するハート
More, more, and more, an accelerating heart,
行くよどこまでも 準備は OK?
we'll go anywhere! Are you ready?
開け 夢の扉を!
Open the door to our dreams!
重ねた手は ギュッと離さずに
Our joined hands, holding tight without letting go,
描くよ ときめき
we draw our heart-fluttering excitement!
振り向くことなく まっすぐに
Without looking back, straight ahead,
行くよ 夢見る空へ
we go toward the sky of our dreams!
笑い合ったことや 尽きそうにない思い出
Laughing together, endless memories,
いっぱいなのに
even though there are so many...
あと少しの音 響かせて
let a few more notes resonate!
何も言わないで ハート
Don't say anything, heart...
どれも全部大事でいいの
Every single part of it is precious.
ワン、ツー
One, two...
みんなのためが力になる
Doing this for everyone gives me strength.
今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
Today is so lively,
笑顔がもう止まらない
I can't stop smiling.
想いは膨らんでいく
These feelings keep swelling up.
重なった今ギューッと噛みしめた
I cherish this moment we share together.
ひとりじゃない
I am not alone.
歌声は広がる
Singing voices spread far and wide.
風を感じたら まっすぐに
Feel the breeze and head straight ahead...
行くよ
Here I go!
夢見る空へ
Towards the sky of my dreams!
背伸びしては手を伸ばす 憧れの
Reaching out on tiptoes towards my admiration,
行き先示す星になろう
I want to become a guiding star showing the way.
つまずくその度に 手を差し述べ合えたら
If we reach out to each other whenever we stumble,
すぐに届くはずさ
we're sure to reach it soon.
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気が
This small step of courage taken softly...
もう消えないように繋げよう
Let's keep it connected so it never fades.
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both our anxieties and fondness tightly,
共に行くよ！
Let me go together with you!
目を合わせて 3, 2, 1!
Lock eyes, 3, 2, 1!
晴れ渡る希望へ
Towards clear, bright hope,
飛び出せるよ！
we can leap forward!
突き抜けていく 僕たちの透き通る決意は
Piercing through, our crystal-clear determination...
まだまだ止められないよ！
can never be stopped!
ありきたりな今日こそ トキメキに変えて
Turning even an ordinary today into excitement,
もっと僕たちがいつまでも 背中押すから！
we'll keep giving you that push from behind forever!
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams,
らしく輝きたい
and shine brightly in my own way.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Crying at times, and laughing together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to look at the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
and seize that dream.
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let me take that miraculous first step!
イキイキとして 夢追いかけたい
Vibrant and lively, I want to chase my dreams.
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement never stops.
想像超えていく
Exceeding imagination,
世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a whole new world.
アクセスしてみない？
Why don't you connect with us?
後悔なんてここにない
There are no regrets here.
それぞれ違ったココロで
With our own unique hearts,
作ろう world
let's create a new world!
はい、ということで
Alright, with that said...
ホロライブ... ホロライブメドレー... 自分の事務所なのに...
The Hololive... Hololive Medley... Even though it's my own agency...
でしたー！
That was the Hololive Medley!
いや、どうだった？なんか激胸だったんじゃないですか？
How was it? Super exciting, right?
そしてね、この衣装は初めてもらったアイドル衣装でございますよ。
And you know, this outfit is the very first idol costume I ever received!
なんかあの時を思い出して、すごいじーんと来てしまいますわね。
Thinking back to those days makes me feel so deeply emotional.
そう、まつりはね、元々その、アイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよ、ホロライブって。
That's right, Hololive didn't start out as an idol group when I debuted.
で、この衣装をもらって、「よし、アイドルとして頑張るぞ！」という気持ちを改めて思い出して、頑張っていくか！という気持ちでございます。
Receiving this outfit reminds me of that "Alright, I'll do my best as an idol!" feeling, inspiring me to keep giving it my all!
はい！そしてそして！今回も！
Yes! And furthermore, this time as well...
誕生日グッズが出まーす！やったー！
Birthday merch is coming out! Yay!
嬉しいー！ということで、1つずつ紹介していきます！
I'm so happy! So let's introduce them one by one!
まずはー、こちら！ドドン！
First up is this! Ta-da!
【薄すぎ！】おっぱいマウスパッド！やったー！
The "Way Too Flat!" Oppai Mousepad! Yay!
イラストはえく先生！
The illustration is by Eku-sensei!
まつりす待望のね、マウスパッドでございますよ！
It's the mousepad that Matsuris have been eagerly waiting for!
あ、ちなみに言うと、膨らみは...ないです。
Ah, by the way... there are no raised bumps on it.
普通のマウスパッドとなっております。
It's just a completely regular mousepad.
こうやって
Like this...
癒すことは難しいんですが
it might be difficult to heal you,
ちょっとガチテレな感じなのでね
but since she looks a bit genuinely embarrassed,
心から癒されていくという感じで
you can feel healed from deep within your heart.
はい どうですか？ 素晴らしいグッズでございましょう
Yes, what do you think? Isn't it a wonderful item?
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
じゃん！ ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Ta-da! Random Acrylic Keychain!
なんと夏色まつり先生の描き下ろしでございますよ！
It features brand-new illustrations drawn by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei herself!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Random Acrylic Keychain!
まつりがグッズのイラスト描くてなかなか無い事でございますから
It's quite rare for Matsuri to draw illustrations for merch,
すごい愛着込めて描きました
so I drew them with lots of love!
もうチュチュチュってしながら描いたので
I drew them while making "chu chu chu" sounds,
ぜひ全種類コンプリートしてみてください！
so please try to complete the full set!
そして続いてはこちら！
And moving on to the next item!
まつりちゃんのぬいぐるみ サブカルジャージ衣装ver.でございます！
Matsuri-chan Plushie Subculture Tracksuit Outfit ver.!
キービジュアルのイラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装の
It's wearing the same subculture tracksuit outfit as in the key visual,
なんとぬい登場しちゃいますよ！
and now it's available as a plushie!
キービジュのように推す推すことは現実だと叶わないけど
While pushing her down like in the key visual isn't possible in real life,
ぬいなら... ぬいならできちゃう！ということで
with a plushie... with a plushie, you can do it!
ぜひたくさん可愛がって色んなとこに連れて行ってあげてください！
So please shower it with lots of love and take it with you everywhere!
さらにはこちら！
Furthermore, we have this!
まつりすマグカップ！
Matsurisu Mug!
みんなにはマグカップになってもらいました！
Everyone, you've been turned into a mug!
「どんな罪を犯してこんな姿になっちまったんだ！」って感じでございますが
Like "What kind of sin did I commit to end up in this form?!"
まぁ自分なのでね
Well, since it's meant to be you,
「これが俺の姿か...」と思いながら使っていただけたらなと思います
I hope you'll use it thinking, "So this is my true form..."
まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます！
Matsuri-chan will be using it too!
最後に
Lastly,
ボイス！ じゃん！
Voice pack! Ta-da!
シチュエーションボイス「逆襲のまつりす」
Situation Voice: "The Counterattack of Matsurisu"
なんだ「逆襲のまつりす」ってなんだ？
What is that? What on earth is "The Counterattack of Matsurisu"?
今回ね、キービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーが
This time, the backstory leading up to the situation in the key visual
ここに詰まっちゃってますので
is packed into this voice pack!
どんなシチュエーションなのか気になる方はぜひゲットしてみてください！
If you're curious about what kind of situation it is, please get your hands on it!
そして！
And!
フルセットを購入いただいた方全員に
To everyone who purchases the Full Set,
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきちゃいます！
you'll receive a postcard with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message!
ちょっとね、来年は直筆やるかちょっとまだ未定でございますので
Whether I'll do handwritten signatures next year is still undecided,
ぜひ全員に書かせていただきますので
so I'll be signing each and every one for everyone!
初めてなんですよ、それも。全員にサイン書くの初めてだから
Actually, this is a first for me too. It's my first time writing signatures for everyone,
ぜひ手に入れてください！
so please be sure to get one!
来年やるかわかんないからね！
Because I don't know if I'll do it next year!
さらにですね！
What's more!
誕生日記念フルセット特典として
As a Birthday Celebration Full Set bonus,
2024年9月から発売された
from September 2024,
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚ついてきちゃいますよ！
you'll get 1 card usable in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
まつりはね、前回のグッズでちょっと特典に付いてなかったので
Since my card wasn't included as a bonus in the previous merch,
今回付いてくるよって感じになっております
this time it's included!
同封する... 同封であってる？日本語
Enclosed... Is "enclosed" the correct Japanese word?
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOPで購入されたお客様の...
Customers who purchase from the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP...
お客様のみの対象となっておりますので、よろしくお願いします
It is exclusive only to customers purchasing from there, so please take note!
特典に付くのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用でき
The card included as a bonus can be used as a single copy in the game,
推しをアピールできるPRカード「推しホロメンカード」でございます！
and it's a PR card "Oshi Holomen Card" to show off your favorite!
そしてそしてそして！さらにでございますよ！まだある！
And, and, and! There's even more! There's still more!
アルバム！
An Album!
デデン！ なんとまつりちゃん...
Ta-da! Believe it or not, Matsuri-chan's...
1st ALBUM『Chasing the Dream ~スポットライトは放課後に~』が
1st Album "Chasing the Dream ~Spotlight After School~"
なんと本日11月1日受注開始でございます！
pre-orders begin today, November 1st!
パパパパン！
Fanfare!
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲「君と眺める夏の花」をはじめ
Starting with Matsuri-chan's very first original song, "Kimi to Nagameru Natsu no Hana",
これまでに配信リリースしてきた作品のほか
as well as tracks previously released digitally,
じんさんをはじめ豪華作曲陣が書き下ろしてくださった
brand-new songs written by luxurious composers like Jin-san
新規楽曲も収録しちゃってますよ！
are also included in this album!
計14曲の超ボリュームなアルバムになっているので、ぜひ手に入れちゃってください！
With a total of 14 tracks, it's a massive album, so please be sure to grab it!
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと
The concept is showcasing both idol Matsuri-chan
普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんのこう
and her usual high school girl self—
両面というか、両方が楽しめるようなアルバムになっています
it's an album where you can enjoy both sides of her!
形態は2つありまして
It comes in two editions:
完全生産限定盤と通常盤をご用意しております
the Complete Limited Production Edition and the Regular Edition.
完全生産限定盤はですね、セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーがついてきちゃいますよ！
The Complete Limited Production Edition comes with a separate-type original calendar!
そして両形態に
And for both editions,
封入特典として、まつりちゃんからの複製お手紙が入っています！
as an included bonus, a replica letter from Matsuri-chan is inside!
ただし！
However!
数量限定のランダムでですね、複製お手紙の代わりに
randomly and in limited quantities, in place of the replica letter,
直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が封入されていますので
a voucher to receive a handwritten letter will be included!
ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください！
So please, please make sure to get your copy!
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album information!
そしてなんと！
And guess what!
アルバムに収録する新曲のうち１曲をですね
One of the new songs included in the album...
本日この後 披露しちゃいます！
...will be performed right here today, right after this!
タイトルは「ウーニャカ」！
The title is "Uunyaka"!
作曲はですね かいりきベアさんに作曲いただきました！ めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It was composed by Kairiki Bear-san! It's super, super cute!
MVもですね この後プレミア公開ありますので
The MV will also have its premiere after this,
0時から あの 楽曲リリースもありますので
and the song will be released at midnight,
あの ぜひ よろしくお願いしますね プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね
so please check it out! Let's watch the premiere together, okay?
はい！
Alright!
じゃあ ちょっと着替えてきますので
Well then, I'm going to go change my outfit,
ちょっとここで待ってて 「ワクワク」って言いながらね ゲストパートと同じように「ワクワク」って言いながら待っててください
so wait here while saying "Waku waku", okay? Just like during the guest part, wait while saying "Waku waku"!
じゃあ 行ってきます！ ワクワク！ ワクワク！
Alright, off I go! Waku waku! Waku waku!
真夜中にトケタ 感情は爪立てて
In the dead of night, melted feelings dig in their claws,
檻から見慣れた 世界は牙向いて
The familiar world beyond the cage bares its fangs.
真夜中 見かねた 感情は飢えた目で
In the dead of night, unbearable emotions gaze with hungry eyes,
軽やかに逃げた 優しさ求めて
Lightly escaping in pursuit of gentleness.
「愛されたい」の想い 愛されないの Give me
"I want to be loved" is my wish, but I'm not loved—give me!
「愛してる」も重い？ 愛さえないの？ もういい？
Is "I love you" too heavy? Is there no love at all? Have you had enough?
愛情結晶頂戴 あなたを見てるのにゃ
Give me a crystal of affection, I'm watching you, meow!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, begging for it,
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めーいっぱい
Come on, tame me, fill me up to the brim!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おでかけ？
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, going out?
しがみついて 何処も行かせない！
Clinging tightly, I won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me sweet candy.
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life.
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
叱らないで頂戴な
Please don't scold me.
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me true "love."
縄張り土足で 感情目丸くして
Entering my territory unannounced, my eyes round with emotion,
幸せになれた 未来が牙向いて
The future where I could be happy bares its fangs.
突き放さないでいて 切り捨てず傍で
Don't push me away, don't cast me aside, stay by my side,
お傍でお傍で見ているのにゃ
Right by your side, right by your side, I'm watching you, meow!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねがい
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, please!
さあ頭撫でて もっと せーいっぱい
Come on, pat my head with all your strength!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おあずけ？
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, put on hold?
甘えて泣いて 此処に居させて！
Let me be spoiled, let me cry, let me stay here!
ニャンニャカ 言ったって伝わんない？
Even if I say "Nyan nyaka", doesn't it reach you?
どーしたって こーしたって寂しいの
No matter what I do, no matter what happens, I'm lonely!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おもいっきり
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, with all my heart,
あざとい声 わざと聞かせる
I intentionally let you hear my sly, charming voice.
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, begging for it,
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めーいっぱい
Come on, tame me, fill me up to the brim!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おやすみ？
Nyan nyaka rin rin rin, good night?
しがみついて 今夜寝かせない！
Clinging tight, I won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me sweet candy.
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life.
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
抱きしめて頂戴な
Hold me close in your arms.
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Uunyaka nyanya uunyanyan,
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me true "love."